Paul Montemayor Jr

@pjmontemayor40@gmail.com



Tacoma, Washington



+1 (253)-579-8371



linkedin.com/in/paul-montemayor-688666202



pjsprojects.github.io

Experience

Journeyman Finish Carpenter

J.R. Abbott Construction



May 2017 – Present

Seattle, WA

- Lead journeymen in charge of onsite team.
- Executed multiple custom projects for clients.
- Experience measuring, cutting, and shaping wood, plastic, and other materials.
- Construct building frameworks, includingwalls, floors, and doorframes.

Maintenance Technician

Echelon Apartments



March 2016 – May 2017

- Inspected buildings, equipment, and systems to identify any issues.
- Repaired faulty equipment units and damaged structures.
- Developed and implemented preventative maintenance procedures.
- Managed heating and plumbing systems to guarantee functionality.
- Planed and scheduled repairs.

Specialized Worker

Roundtight Painting



May 2014 – February 2016

Puyallup, WA

- Demoed and installed hardwood and LVP flooring
- Installed trim packages and custom cabinets
- Executed custom interior millwork painting finishes
- Worked side by side with client to develop and create personalized features and products

Personal Statement

Paul has worked in a variety of construction roles his entire life, with experience in both residential and commercial settings. He specializes in interior finish work, and has a broad skill set across all facets of carpentry. Paul is a self-starter and self-learner but thrives in a team environment.

Volunteerism/Activism

- King County Construction Career Day Answer questions from students interested in internships and apprenticeship programs.
- Sawhorse Revolution Mentor Constructed tiny homes for families living in poor housing conditions while teaching youth the fundamentals of construction.

Education

Carpentry Craft Training Program Construction Industry Training Council of WA



2017 - 2020

Washington State University Pullman, WA



September 2014-January 2016

Technical Skills

- Welding/Fabrication
- Flux Core, MIG, soldering Low Volt Circuitry

12 volt automotive, solar power supply

- Woodworking Interior trim packages, custom cabinets, doors
- Finishes Airless, HVLP, Pressure Pot, Gravity Feed, LVLP